Guide to the Samuel R. Delany Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- May 2017 acquisition, 200.17; (249 boxes) + 1 record album storage
  - Materials deposited circa 1999, 1947-1999; 51.75; (52 boxes)
    - Journals, 1974-1999
      - 1970s
        - Journals, circa 1977 April, circa 1977 summer (Box 58)
          Includes: notes for 'American Shore'; poem: "Does Meaning Cleave More to the Trembling Thing"; notes for 'Stars'; fragment beginning "She saw him minutes after she'd murdered..."; 'Stars'; "Preface to the Winhover Edition"; "The Liquid Text"; "'Driftglass'--a note on the text"; letter to Henry Louis Gates Jr.; poem: "Beginnings".
        - Journals, circa 1977 Fall (Box 58)
          Includes: story with characters Qrelon, Akbrum, and Wryn, including illustrations; notes for "Eridani"; "Introduction" (to 'American Shore'?).
        - Journals, 1977 September - December, 1977 (Box 58)
          Includes: continuation of illustrated story in 1977 Fall journal; "S-F and Technology"; class notes; color photographs of SRD getting a tattoo; notes for story with Qrelon et al.; "Tales of Neveryon (?)". Locations specified as Milwaukee and Wisonsin.
        - Journals, circa 1977 (Box 58)
          Includes: story with Qrelon et al.; letters to Tom Disch, NYPD; 'Stars'; recording of a dream; "Early Poems of Marilyn Hacker, transcribed from memory, by SR Delany"; class notes (?); 'Tales of Neveryon'.
        - Journals, 1978- (Box 58)
          Includes: letters to Gayatri Spivak, Frederic Jameson, Richard Howard.
        - Journals, 1978(?) (Box 58)
          Includes: story with Qrelon et al.; "S-F and 'Literature'"; notes for 'Stars'; essay on Joanna Russ; letters to "Gentlemen" and "Frank"; "Poetics/Science Fiction/Semiotics".
        - Journals, 1978 spring, 1978 September (Box 58)
          Includes: notes for edited collection of Disch stories; 'Tales of Neveryon'; letter to Dr. Peplow; "The Interviewer's View of the Project/Enterprise"; children's poems; 'Stars'; letter to Shoshana Felman; "P/F".
        - Journals, 1978 September, 1978 October (Box 58)
          Includes: 'Tales of Neveryon'; 'Stars'; letters to "Carol", Robert Louit, Dr. Peplow, Frederic Jamesson, Iva to Marilyn Hacker; postcards of Capucine Cemetery and Greek ruins; Traves entries (Greece); "Mattematica" (poem by Marilyn Hacker); letters to Frederic Jamesson; notes for 'Heavenly Breakfast'.
        - Journals, 1978 December - 1979 March, circa 1979 (Box 59)
          Includes: 'Stars'; "Do you think science fiction should be taken seriously as literature?"; "P/F"; "Delany Chronology"; letters to "Pep", Joanna Russ, "Garry", "Brian".
        - Journals, circa 1979, 1979 June (Box 59)
          Includes: 'Tales of Neveryon'; "P/F" (?); notes on 'Stars'; letter to Joanna Russ; "P/F".
        - Journals, 1979 July, 1979 Summer/Autumn (Box 59)
          Includes: 'Stars'; letter to Pep, Misha (?); autobiographical reflections; "Literature, Myth and the African World"; letters to Patrick, Pep; "A Theory of Science Fiction"; "P/F"; travel entries (Baltimore, Rotterdam/Rome); response to "Prof. Parrinder's refiew of SRD's work".
        - Journals, circa 1979 October (Box 59)
          'Stars'; letters to Michael Peplow, Joanna Russ, Patrick; "The Albert"; introduction to 'Starboard Wine'; "P/F".
        - Journals, 1979 November (Box 59)
          Includes: 'Stars'; introduction to 'Starboard Wine'; letter to Michael Peplow; story involving Qrelon; "Lou Christie(?)".
      - 1980s
        - Journals, 1980?, circa 1980 March (Box 59)
          Includes: 'Stars'; Iva Hacker-Delany (?) scribbles; letters to Mog, Norman Kagan; "On the Deaths of James Wright and Roland Barthes"; "P/F".
        - Journals, 1980 spring, circa 1980 May (Box 59)
          Includes: 'Stars'; 'Neveryona'; "Positivistic Criticism"; "Autobiography"; Howe Caverns brochure; 'Dhalgren' review excerpts; essay on S-F; letters to Robert Bravard, Shoshana Feldman, "Richard", George Lucas, Mog, Doug; "The Critical Act"; "Creeps"; brochure for Belmont Park; photograph of SRD and two others.
        - Journals, early summer, 1980 summer (Box 59)
          Includes: essay on Foucault and sexuality; story with characters Vondra and Glynda; introductory essay to story collection; "Russel Fitz Gerald"; postcard of "Wingspread"; notes for 'Stars', 'Starboard Wine'; preface; nottes for Frank Romeo's film; "The Aunts".
        - Journals, 1980 summer (Box 59)
          Includes: essay on poetry; 'Stars'; entries and memorailia from trips to New Orleans, California, Pacific Northwest, Vancouver; notes for Mog; notes for 'Neveryona'.
        - Journals, 1980 November, 1980 winter (Box 59)
          Includes: 'Stars'; essay on SF; "'In Absolutely No Time at All...' or A Critique of 'Sweet Virginia'"; "The Jewel of the 7th Sun"; reproductions of paintings; "P/F(?)"; letters to Ihab Hassan, Bob Bravard, Tom Disch; essay on Tom Disch.
        - 'Neveryon' I, 1980-08- (Box 59)
          Includes: 'Neveryona' draft.
        - 'Neveryon' II, circa 1980 (Box 59)
        - 'Neveryon' III, circa 1980 (Box 59)
        - 'Neveryon' IV, 1980-12- (Box 59)
          Includes: 'Neveryona' draft; 'Stars' Part II, chapter II.
        - 'Neveryon' V; 'Neveryon' Va, circa 1980 - 1981 (Box 59)
          Includes: 'Neveryona' draft; essay on Artaud; essay on being gay.
        - 'Neveryon' Vb; 'Neveryon' VI, circa 1980 - 1981 (Box 59)
          Includes: 'Neveryona' draft; letter to Michael Peplow; letters to Walter Abish, Kay Saunders, Stanley Fish.
        - 'Neveryon' VII; 'Neveryon' VIII, circa 1980 - 1981 (Box 59)
          Includes: 'Neveryona' draft; "Science Fiction and Deconstruction"; letter to Mog; letter to Joanna Russ.
        - Journals, circa 1981 June/July, circa 1981 September (Box 59)
          Includes: 'Neveryona'; letters to Mog; letter to 'Foundation'; early draft of 'Motion'; photoprints of conference on innovation in Western culture (Milwaukee, 1981); travel entries, postcards, and brochures from trip to the Southwest.
        - Journals, circa 1981 October (Box 60)
          Includes: letters to Mog, Bob; essay on Wagner; 'Neveryona'; travel memorabilia; 'Stars'; letters to Bob Bravard, STH.
        - Journals, circa 1981 December, circa 1982 January (Box 60)
          Includes: 'Stars'; 'Neveryona'; photoprints of Christmas 1981; autobiographical reflections; letter to Joanna Russ; "The Mind of the Moralist Revisited"; "The Travels of Iva"; 'Flight from Neveryon'.
        - Journals, 1982 February, 1982 (Box 60)
          Includes: 'Stars'; family tree; personal entries; letters to Mog, Andreas, Bob Bravard; notes for 'Driftglass/Starshards'; "The Right of the Reader"; "Non-SF pieces I would like to write"; "Text and Context, or Aries, Aries Rising: Autobiographical Notes".
        - Journals, circa 1982 July, 1982 July 28 - 1982 September 26 (Box 60)
          Includes: 'Stars'; letters to Joanna Russ, Bob Bravard, Seth; personal entries; stories by Mike Elkins.
        - Journals, 1982 July 28 - October 4, circa 1982 October - December (Box 60)
          Includes: 'Stars'; letters to Bob Bravard, Mog; "Laughter"; untitled poems; preface to 'Straits'; personal entries; introduction to 'Driftglass/Starshards'; "Waiting for Jeff"; notes on earliest writings; 'Straits of Messina' (?); miscellany re: theater productions; "The Tale of Fog and Granite"; "Elegy for Bernie"; "To My Dads" (note from Iva Hacker-Delany).
        - Journals, circa 1982 February 8, circa 1983 January - March (Box 60)
          Includes: "The Tale of Fog and Granite"; "Funeral Song"; photoprints of Christmas 1982; "Sentences"; "Wagner and Artaud"; personal entries; "Tale of Plagues and Carnivals"; letter to Bob Bravard; responses to unidentified inerview questions; essay on computers.
        - Journals, 1983 February?, circa 1983 March (Box 60)
          Includes: "Notes on Ecco's 'The Tree and the Maze'"; "P/F" (?); MLA address (?); letter to Seth; personal entries; poem: "Perseus" (?); photoprints of SRD's study, Marc Gawron, Frank Romeo; letters to Donald Allen, James Harkness; "Boca Raton".
        - Journals, 1983 April - June, circa 1983 June 19 (Box 60)
          Includes: notes for 'Splendor'; personal entries and dream recordings; letter to Guy Davenport; "Tale of Fog and Granite"; miscellany re: trip to Metz; personal entries; piece on John Brunner; letters to Don, Iva Hacker-Delany, Jule; Iva Hacker-Delany passport; 'Mad Man' (?).
        - Journals, circa 1983 August, circa 1983 October 10 (Box 60)
          Includes: "Wagner/Artaud"; reflections and clippings on Ring Cycle; poster for Barbara Wise and SRD; reading of "Heat Death of the Universe"; personal entries; photoprints of Wise and SRD; "Tale of Fog and Granite"; postcard from Frank Romeo (1983 September); 'Mad Man' (?).
        - Journals, circa 1983 October 28, circa 1983 December 7 (Box 60)
          Includes: "Tale of Fog and Granite"; "On Breaking Margaret's Teacup..."; letter to Mary; 'Mad Man' (?); autobiographical fragments; personal entries.
        - Journals, circa 1984 January, circa 1984 February (Box 60)
          Includes: "Tale of Fog and Granite"; letters to Lou, Tom LeClare, Marilyn Hacker; personal entries; "The Mummer's Tale"; letter to Michael Peplow; "The Pit" (?).
        - Journals, 1984 February - March, 1984 spring (Box 60)
          Includes: personal entries; notes on Wagner; letter to Bob Bravard; 'Flight'; miscellaneous flyers, theater programs, postcards; "Tale of Plagues and Carnivals"; "The Pit" (?); notes on women and transhistoricity; notes on sex and S-F.
        - Journals, 1984 April - May, 1984 June (Box 60)
          Includes: personal entries; "Tale of Plagues and Carnivals"; poem: "To a Passing Woman"; notes on studies of Baudelaire; "Money Diary"; "The Pit" (?).
        - Journals, 1984 July (Box 60)
          Includes: "The Pit" (?); personal entries; notes on Joseph Campbell lecture; ghosted letter to Umbert Ecco; essay on The Ring Cycle; letters to Bob Bravard, Ron Drummond; notes for 'Splendor/Misery'; dream recordings; "Thoughts on Raymond Carver after Adorno".
        - Journals, circa 1984 September, circa 1984 November 20 (Box 60)
          Includes: personal entries; Contradiction 4 program book; photoprints of Halloween 1984; 'Mad Man' (?); miscellany re: Election Day; "The Pit" (?); sketch for cover of 'Flight'; note from Frank Romeo (1984 December 1); book notes; advertising and short reviews of 'Stars'; "Exercise for Ferne's Play Writing Workshop"; note from Iva Hacker-Delany; photoprints of Christmas 1984; 'Mad Man' (?).
        - Journals, circa 1985 January, circa 1985 Feruary (Box 60)
          Includes: 'Return to Neveryon'; personal entries; "P/F" (?); 'Splendor/Misery'; notes on film 'Rated X'; letters from Frank Romeo; "In the Once Upon a Time City" ('Locus', 1985 February); comments on Haraway's paper; "X"; miscellany re: "Age of Caravaggio".
        - Journals, circa 1985 March 10, 1985 May - June (Box 60)
          Includes: letter from Leo Cawley; essay on Donna Haraway; personal entries; notes on Olsen lecture by Diane DiPrima; 'Mad Man' (?); miscellaneous notes, transcripts, programs; Michelle Schwartz to Iva Hacker-Delany (1985 April 11); "Foreword to an Afterword"; photoprints of Pet Perum, SRD accepting Pilgrim Award.
        - Journals, 1985 June - August (Box 60)
          Includes: personal entries; Peter Perun to Polish Consulate (1985 June 4); 'Mad Man' (?).
        - Journals, 1985 September 21 - November 3, undated - late 1970s? (Box 61)
          Includes: 'Splendor/Misery'; 'Return'; letter from Ursula K. Le Guin (1985 September 30); address on the difference between SF and fantasy; photoprints of SRD at Novacon 3; notes on critical reading of Disch; letters to Tom Disch (undated, late 1970s?).
        - Journals, 1985 November 4 - December 23, circa 1985 December 24 (Box 61)
          Includes: photoprint of Iva Hacker-Delany; "P/F" (?); theater and travel memorabilia; Morrison Agency Christmas party invitation with SRD's notes; daily personal entries; photoprints of Joe Manfredini, SRD, and others at 1986 PEN S-F Panel; "Notes on the Illiad"; miscellaneous postcards, ticket stubs, advertisements.
        - Journals, circa 1986 (Box 61)
          Includes: "My Bedside notebook"; "P/F" (?).
        - Journals, 1986 February 12, 1986 April - June (Box 61)
          Includes: "Behold Her Silver Hooves (Split Silver?)"; notes for 'Semiology of Silence'; personal entries; two letters from Robert Philmus (1986 March 4); miscellaneous thater programs, ticket stubs, receipts, announcements; introductory comments to "Tale of Plagues and Carnivals" with Barbara Wise; miscellaneous ticket stubs, brochures; "Power Sign/Text"; daily personal entries.
        - Journals, 1986 June 15 - July 27, circa 1986 July 28 (Box 61)
          Includes: 4 letters from Iva Hacker-Delany to SRD (1986 June 8, June 11, undated); promotional letter re: Hacker; 'Love, Death, and the Changing of the Seasons'; miscellaneous programs, postcards; essay on trash; letters from Richard Kostelanetz (1986 June), Laurel Bernard (1986 June 9); daily personal entries; entry by David G. Hartwell; miscellaneous notes, postcards, and letters; reflections on race.
        - Journals, circa 1986 August 31, circa 1986 October 1 (Box 61)
          Includes: photoprint of SRD (1985 spring); letter from Luise White; class syllabus for SRD's "Science Fiction, Psychoanalysis, and Society"; lecture notes; phone messages; miscellaneous receipts, postcards, programs, clippings; daily personal entries; photoprint of SRD (1986 April 20); notes from students; daily personal entries especially re: experiences at Corness University; review of 'Alien'; miscellaneous programs, invitations, tickets; daily personal entries, especially re: experiences at University of Kansas and Cornell University; lists of interview questions; miscellaneous letters and notes to SRD.
        - Journals, circa 1986 October 31, circa 1986 November 30 (Box 61)
          Includes: daily personal entries; reflections on Donna Haraway's "Manifesto for Cyborgs"; notes, phone messages, and letters to SRD; postcards, programs, tickets, and announcements; photoprints of SRD and Barbara Wise, Skip Gates and Anthony Appiah, Iva Hacker-Delany, Ken James (?), students; Ken James interview; notes on family history; "Oysters for Christmas"; clippings, programs, tickets.
        - Journals, circa 1987 January, circa 1987 January 29, 1987 March 8 - April 13 (Box 61)
          Includes: personal entries; letters to "Lew" and Luise White; notes on annual MLA and other meetings; letters from Henry Louis Gates, Jr. (1987 January 13), Nicholas Delbanco (1987 January 5); untitled address for 1987 SERCON; 'Bridge'; postcards, programs, photoprints; photoprints, programs, nametags, tickets.
        - Journals, circa 1987 April 15 (Box 61)
          Includes: notes for UMass lecture; personal entries; letter from Carl Sagan (1987 April 28); photoprints, letters, notes, and programs.
        - Journals, 1987 June - July, circa 1987 July 13 (Box 61)
          Includes: 'Motion'; personal entries; photoprints, postcards, announcements; letters from Iva Hacker-Delany (July 11, July 12, July 27, July 29); intro to reading of "Tale of Rumor and Desire".
        - Journals, 1987 August, 1987 September - October (Box 61)
          Includes: 'Motion'; personal entries; letter from George Stambolian (1987 August 17); reviews of 'Bridge'; letter from Darnell Schweizer (1987 September 28); miscellany re: Zurbaran show at Met.
        - Journals, circa 1987 October 15, circa 1987 November 11 (Box 61)
          Includes: personal entries; miscellany re: speaking engagements in Washington, D.C.; original cartoon by William Gibson; 'Wagner/Artaud'; "The Space of Disfiguration"; programs for several art shows.
        - Journals, 1987 November 27 - 1988 January 1, 1988 January 1 (Box 61)
          Includes: personal entries; miscellany re: speaking engagements in Rochester, NY; reviews of 'Bridge'; reviews of 'Motion' and 'Bridge'.
        - Journals, circa 1988 February 4, circa 1988 March 22 (Box 61)
          Includes: personal entries; introduction to reading of "Tale of Plagues and Carnivals"; interview with Al Cunningham; announcements, programs, clippings, postcards; documents re: Danny McLaughlin criminal case; correspondence re: Danny McLaughlin case; photoprints, postcards, programs, announcements; autobiographical notes; letter from James A. Glover (1988 April 20).
        - Journals, circa 1988 May 13, circa 1988 June 13 (Box 62)
          Includes: personal entries; reviews of 'Motion' and 'Bridge'; photoprints, letters, postcards, programs; insert: "My First Three Meetings with Mason Bailey", computerscript (1988 May 13); "Notes on Paula Robinson's galleys for 'Generation'"; notes on Clarion '88; clippings on Tom Disch and Pamela Zoline.
        - Journals, circa 1988 July 23, circa 1988 August 6 (Box 62)
          Includes: personal entries; letter from Steven R. Boyett (1988 July 16); newsclippings on Clarion '88; interview with Constance Penley and Sharon Willis; miscellany re: trip to Provincetown; letter from David Hartwell (1988 September 1).
        - Journals, circa 1988 September 5, 1988 October - November (Box 62)
          Includes: personal entries; notes and miscellany re: UMass class; clippings on Ingmar Bergman, Times Square renovation, synagogue vandalism; class notes; James Thomson material; clipping re: Greenfield, MA murder case.
        - Journals, 1988 November - December, circa 1988 December 21 (Box 62)
          Includes: class notes; train and bus tickets; theater programs; interview with Constance Penley and Sharon Willis; personal entries; book notes (?).
        - Journals, 1989 February, 1989 March (Box 62)
          Includes: personal entries; "1987-1988 Publications"; class notes; miscellany re: trip to Philadelphia; faculty meeting notes (?); SRD's favorite photo of Iva Hacker-Delany; essay on film; notes from John Del Grazio; Palm Sunday order of service; "Reading Since September".
        - Journals, 1989 April - May, circa 1989 April 20 (Box 62)
          Includes: personal entries; class notes; miscellany re: Wagner's Ring Cycle at Metropolitan Opera; clippings on closing of Goliard Bookshop; insert: "Creativity and Academic Writing", computerscript with holographic corrections (1989 May 16); "Books Read in my Modernist Novel Course, 1988-1989"; review of "Hurricane Trio"; miscellany re: Literature of Science Fiction Conference; AIDS fundraiser; "Absent Moon"; 'Neveryona' revisions; theater programs.
        - Journals, circa 1989 July 12, 1989 August (Box 62)
          Includes: letters from Iva Hacker-Delany (1989 July 13), Marge Piercy; letter to Keith Kilman; miscellany re: trip to Norway; notes on Castle Hill Workshop; personal entries; photoprint of SRD receiving 1989 Hugo Award; miscellany re: Norcason III; class notes; department meeting notes; articles on S-F; letter from Larry McCaffery (1989 September 3).
        - Journals, 1989 September, circa 1989 October 10 (Box 62)
          Includes: "The Artist's Journey into the Interior"; faculty meeting notes (?); class notes; personal entries; "Leaving New York" (photocopy of 1969 writing); "Notes on a Conversation with Judith Merrill"; progression of SRD reading at The Dark Room.
        - Journals, 1989 November, circa 1989 December 25 (Box 62)
          Includes: personal entries; class notes; notes for The Dump; brochures, letters, programs; faculty meeting minutes (?); order of service at Stephen Wise Free Synagogue; miscellaneous photos, letters; "50 Great T. Sturgeon Stories"; notes for SF, psychoanalysis, and the state; essay on Sturgeon and Bester; notes on heads and chairs meeting; Graduate Course Studies Committee meeting.
      - circa 1990s
        - Journals, 1990 February, 1990 March (Box 62)
          Includes: printed matter and ntoes on Queer Theory conference at UC Santa Cruz; essay on art an dobsession; "Teaching Notes on 'Driftglass'"; miscellany re: Norman, Oklahoma appearance; meeting notes; notes on Novalis; class notes; personal entries; "Barbara Wise's Player's Club Application"; essay on 'Murder in the Rue Morgue'.
        - Journals, circa 1990 March 26, 1990 April - May (Box 62)
          Includes: class notes; notes on talk by Stan Robinson; meeting notes for Heads and Chairs Committee and others; notes on "The Orchid"; personal entries; miscellany re: "The Ring"; interview questions from Robert F. Reid-Farr.
        - Journals, circa 1990 May 23, 1990 July (Box 62)
          Includes: personal entries; meeting notes; "'Nova' Commentary"; letters from Fran Zimmerman, Keith Keilman; "Twilight in the Rue Morgue"; essays on Haraway, Le Guin; "The Dump" (?); "On Reading"; insert: tribute to Ethyl Eichelberger; notes on Cape Cod environmental panel.
        - Journals, circa 1990 August 25, circa 1990 October 5 (Box 62)
          Includes: "The Life of/and Writing"; essays on 'esthetic psychology'; personal entries; "The Dump" (?); essay on 'Return to Neveryon'; notes on Derrida; letter to Jim Sallis; essay on Haraway; "The Dead Mall".
        - Journals, circa 1990 November 7, 1990 December (Box 62)
          Includes: response to Clarion Papers; personal entries; essay on Poe; essays on Haraway; 'The Dump'; Christmas poem from Tom Disch; photoprint of Quentin Llorente; NY Times obit and funeral program for Hubert T. Delany; Byatt review essay.
        - Journals, 1991 January, 1991 March (Box 62)
          Includes: personal entries; Gulf War protest leaflets, clippings; miscellaneous letters, clippings; notes for "The Dead Mall"; essay on John Brunner; class notes; heads and chairs meeting notes; letter to Larry McCaffery; 'The Dump'; essay on AIDS.
        - Journals, circa 1991 March 31, circa 1991 May 14 (Box 62)
          Includes: meeting notes; essay on Haraway; birthday greetings; personal entries; 'The Dump' (?); class notes; "It's Just a Thing"; postcards of NYC; autobiographical reflections; 'They Fly at Ciron'; Iva Hacker-Delany report card.
        - Journals, circa 1991 June 20, circa 1991 July 17 (Box 62)
          Includes: personal entries; miscellany re: Germany trip; miscellany re: Gay Pride Day; Readercon panel notes; photoprint of Iva Hacker-Delany; "Manual of First Congregational Church", Amherst, MA (1880); miscellaneous letters and notes to SRD; notes for 'Mad Man' (?); 'Phallos' (?); notes for Clarions 1-5; postcards of Seattle, Cleveland; notes for reading "Citre et Trans" at Cleveland State.
        - Journals, circa 1991 August 14, circa 1991 September 22 (Box 63)
          Includes: personal entries; 'Phallos' (?); two tickets to Bronx High School of Science Commencement, 1960 June 27; miscellaneous letters; class notes; 'They Fly at Ciron'; syllabus for "Introduction to Science Fiction"; meeting notes; notes for "My Father's Family"; 'Hogg' (?).
        - Journals, circa 1991 November 2, circa 1991 December 21 (Box 63)
          Includes: photoprints for SRD and Dennis Rickett, and others; class notes; notes on lost 1991 October 18 notebook; personal entries; clippings on Delany sisters; meeting notes; notes on "The Dead Mall"; revisions for 'They Fly at Ciron'; miscellaneous letters; card from Ntozake Shange; SRD to Iva Hacker-Delany, 1991 Christmas (illustrated); signed pen and ink drawing by Gregory Flux; miscellaneous clippings, letters, and notes; 'Mad Man' (?).
        - Journals, circa 1992 January 24, circa 1992 March 15 (Box 63)
          Includes: clippings, letters, and broadsides; personal entries; class notes; notes for "Shadow and Ash"; meeting notes; "Shadow and Ash"; miscellaneous clippings, especially re: Bruce Springsteen; miscellany re: Lunacon; various speaking engagements; notes on meeting with chancellor of UMass.